Mss.B.H334
American Philosophical Society
- Papers, 1.75 lin. feet 4 upright boxes, 1 volume
  - Churchill, F. to Isaac Hays, 1852 Aug. 25; Mss.B.H334
  - Churchill, J. to Isaac Hays, 1842-1850; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1842 Dec. 6, 1850.
    1967 940ms (1842), 1967 562ms (1850)
  - Civiale to Isaac Hays, 1839-1848; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1839 Dec. 26, 1848 Jan. 16
  - Clark, A. to Isaac Hays, 1874 Mar. 9; Mss.B.H334
  - Clark, W. to Isaac Hays, 1835 Jul. 7; Mss.B.H334
  - Clarke, Edward H. to Isaac Hays, 1857 Jun. 29; Mss.B.H334
  - Cohen, Mindes to I. Minis Hays, 1899 Oct. 14; Mss.B.H334.1
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons of Philadelphia to I. Minis Hays, 1903 Mar. 6; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Collins, R. to Isaac Hays, 1839 Jul. 11; Mss.B.H334
  - Collins, Z. to Isaac Hays, 1824-undated; Mss.B.H334
    3 items: 1824 May 21, 1831 May 25, undated Oct. 24
  - Colonial Society of Massachusetts to I. Minis Hays, 1910-undated; Mss.B.H334.1
    6 items: 3 invitations, 2 replies, 1 envelope.
  - Combe, George to Isaac Hays, 1839 Feb. 12; Mss.B.H334
  - Cotton, R. P. to Isaac Hays, 1849 Jul. 16; Mss.B.H334
  - Coxe, J. R. to Isaac Hays, 1834 Sep.; Mss.B.H334
  - Crittenden, J. J. to Isaac Hays, 1851-1852; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1851 Oct. 24, 1852 Jun. 10
  - Cuvier, Georges Leopold Chretien Frederic Dagobert, baron to Isaac Hays, 1826 Jan. 9; Mss.B.H334
  - Cuyler, John M. to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
    September 18.
  - Darlington, William to Isaac Hays, 1854 Dec. 22; Mss.B.H334
  - Davis, N. S. to Isaac Hays, 1850 Mar. 15; Mss.B.H334
  - Deabatte, G. to Isaac Hays, 1824 May 25; Mss.B.H334
  - Delarze(?) to I. Minis Hays, 1885 Aug. 3; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Denisend(?), George B., 1907 Feb. 11; Mss.B.H334.1
  - De Saussure, Henry W. to Isaac Hays, 1851 Apr. 17; Mss.B.H334
  - Detwold, William to Isaac Hays, 1849 Nov. 14; Mss.B.H334
  - Devinny(?), F. P. to Isaac Hays, 1846 Mar. 20; Mss.B.H334
  - Dewees, William P. to Isaac Hays, 1839 Dec. 23; Mss.B.H334
  - Dickinson
    Unlocated June 2011. Possibly refers to Dixon or Dickinson.
  - Dickson to I. Minis Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334.1
    January 21. Reply from Hays on the back.
  - Dillwyn, L. W. to Isaac Hays, 1824 Feb. 7; Mss.B.H334
  - Dixon, Samuel G. to I. Minis Hays, 1901 Nov. 29; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Doane, G. W. to Isaac Hays, 1847 Mar. 1; Mss.B.H334
  - Drake, C. to Isaac Hays, 1831 Feb. 12; Mss.B.H334
  - Drake, Daniel to Isaac Hays, 1827-1828; Mss.B.H334
    1967 525ms (1828 Feb. 13), 1967 940ms (1827s, 1828 Apr. 26)
    5 items: 1827 May 22, 1827 Jun. 22, 1827 Nov. 21, 1828 Feb. 13, 1828 Apr. 26
  - Draper, Charles M. to Isaac Hays, 1838 May 4; Mss.B.H334
  - Draper, John William to Isaac Hays, 1837-1851; Mss.B.H334
    3 items: 1837 Jul. 22, 1851 Nov. 5, 1851 Nov. 22.
    1967 525 (1851 Nov. 3), 1967 562ms (1851 Nov. 22), 1967 940ms (1837)
  - Du Bois, A. to Isaac Hays, 1848 Oct. 28; Mss.B.H334
  - Eames, Wilberforce to I. Minis Hays, 1898 Aug. 1; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Ellis, Charles to Isaac Hays, 1843; Mss.B.H334
  - Emerson, G. to Isaac Hays, 1839 Oct. 21; Mss.B.H334
    On the same sheet as letter from Randolph.
  - Engel, Dr. to Isaac Hays, 1878 Feb. 12; Mss.B.H334
  - Esmarch, D. to I. Minis Hays, 1889 May 5; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Ewing, Maskell from I. Minis Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334.1
    December 14.
  - Fahnestock, William M. to Isaac Hays, 1833-1840; Mss.B.H334
    1967 525ms (1831, 1833), 1967 562ms (1840 Sep. 24), 1967 940ms (1840 Feb. 29)
    4 items: 1831 Jul. 6, 1833 May 13, 1840 Feb. 29, 1840 Sep. 24
  - Featherstonehaugh Controversy, 1831; Mss.B.H334
    15 items:
    George William Featherstonehaugh to Hays: 1831 Feb. 11 and 1831 Aug. 3 Hays's reply to Featherstonehaugh: 1831 Aug. 2 George W. Smith to Featherstonehaugh: 1831 Aug. 3 (3 letters) Statement by Franklin Peale, Reuben Haines, Henry Carey, A. D. Bache, Isaac Lea, and ?: May 1831 Copy of a statement by Richard Harlan: undated Copies of letters, bound by ribbon: Hays to Featherstonehaugh (Aug. 2, #1), G. W. Smith to Featherstonehaugh (Aug. 3, #2), Featherstonehaugh to Smith (Aug. 3, 1:30, #3), Smith to Featherstonehaugh (Aug. 3, 3:00, #4), Featherstonehaugh to Smith (Aug. 3, #5), Smith to Featherstonehaugh (Aug. 3, #6), third person presumably Featherstonehaugh to Smith (Aug. 4, #7)
  - Fisher, John D. to Isaac Hays, 1827-1845; Mss.B.H334
    1967 525ms (1843 Oct. 14, 1843 Sep. 2, 1843 May 31, 1842 Mar. 22, 1841 Oct. 19, 1838 Oct. 17, 1838 Mar. 27, 1827 May 11, 1827 Jun. 6), 1967 562ms (1845 Feb. 11), 1967 940ms (1838 Feb. 10, 1838 Mar. 21, 1838 May 23, 1838 Dec. 5, 26, 1844 Feb. 27)
    16 items. Fisher to Hays: 1827 Jun. 6, 1838 Feb. 10, 1838 Mar. 21, 1838 Mar. 27, 1838 May 23, 1838 Oct. 17, 1838 Dec. 5, 1838 Dec. 26, 1841 Oct. 19, 1842 Mar. 22, 1843 May 31, 1843 Sep. 2, 1843 Oct. 14, 1845 Feb. 11. Hays to Fisher: 1844 Feb. 27. Fisher to William E. Horner: 1827 May 11.
  - Flint, Austin to Isaac Hays, 1881-1885; Mss.B.H334
    9 items: 1881 Jan. 25, 1881 Feb. 25, 1881 Mar. 26, 1876 Sep. 22, 1885 May 9, 1885 May 15, 1885 Jun. 13, 1885 Aug. 6, 1885 Aug. 14
  - Francis, John W. to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
  - Franklin Institute to Isaac Hays, 1828-1840; Mss.B.H334
    18 items.
  - Free Library of Philadelphia to I. Minis Hays, 1898-1900; Mss.B.H334.1
    2 items: 1898 Sep. 20, 1900 May 5
  - Frick, Louis Dreka to I. Minis Hays, 1884 Dec. 10; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Friedenwald, Herbert to I. Minis Hays, 1898 Oct. 2; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Furness, H. H. to I. Minis Hays, 1892-undated; Mss.B.H334.1
    1967 525ms (1908, undated), 1967 562ms (1892, 1896, 1899, 1907)
    6 items: 1892 Feb. 5, 1896 Dec. 13, 1899 Jan. 9, 1907 Feb. 25, 1908 Mar. 25, undated Dec. 1
  - Furness, W. H. to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
  - Ghinozzi, G. C. to Isaac Hays, 1876 Feb. 6; Mss.B.H334
  - Gardner, W. V. to I. Minis Hays, 1891 Oct. 22; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Glendenning, John to Isaac Hays, 1834 Jul. 8; Mss.B.H334
  - Gliddon, Dr. to Isaac Hays, 1856 Jun. 12; Mss.B.H334
  - Godman, John D. to Isaac Hays, 1826; Mss.B.H334
    1967 525ms, 562ms, 940ms
    2 items: 5 Dec., 8 Dec.
    The initials "H.E.U." are used by Godman. Reason unknown. 7/15/81 J.S.C. [See endorsement on letter of July 30, 1827]
  - Godman, John D. to Isaac Hays, 1827; Mss.B.H334
    29 items: Jan. 2, 7, 17, 18, 26; Feb. 1, 15, 20; May 26; June 8, 17, 22; July 1, 5, 13, 15, 30; Aug. 3, 7, 14, 16, 23; Sept. 10, 19, 28; Nov. 15; Dec. 4, 10, 24.
  - Godman, John D. to Isaac Hays, 1828; Mss.B.H334
    7 items: Jan. 13, 15; Feb. 19; March 8, undated; Monday; Thursday.
  - Godman, John D. to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
    4 items.
  - Goodyear, Charles to Isaac Hays, 1848 Jun. 21; Mss.B.H334
  - Grateloup to Isaac Hays, 1836-1838; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1836 Jan. 11, 1838 Jan. 28
  - Gratz, Benjamin from Isaac Hays, 1819 May 23; Mss.B.H334
  - Gratz, Simon to I. Minis Hays, 1898 Sep. 30; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Green, Samuel A. from I. Minis Hays, 1898 Feb. 23; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Griffith, R. E. to Isaac Hays, 1837 Sep. 1; Mss.B.H334
  - Gross, Samuel David to Isaac Hays, 1871-undated; Mss.B.H334
    1967 525ms (1871), 1967 562ms (1884, undated)
    4 items: 1871 Mar. 14; 1884 Mar. 14, 15; undated Mar. 23.
  - Haines, Reuben to Isaac Hays, 1823 Nov. 7; Mss.B.H334
  - Halberstadt, A. H. to Isaac Hays, 1886; Mss.B.H334
    Printed Action of the American Medical Association calling for all members of the Ninth International Medical Conference (1887) to be in accord with the National Code of Ethics. "Endorsed" is crossed out, and Halbertstadt's handwritten note expresses the opinion that the "question of code is simply a transparent subterfuge...medico-political chicanery."
    Signed by William H. Paulvart (?), William B. Atkinson, and P. D. Keyser; orientation may indicate endorsement of the printed Action.
  - Hall, Marshall to Isaac Hays, 1853; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1853 Jul. 29, Sep. 27
  - Hamilton, W. to Isaac Hays, 1833; Mss.B.H334
    Appointments to the Franklin Institute's committee on publications. (Date is somewhat unclear; may be 1823 rather than 1833.)
  - Harris, L. to Isaac Hays, 1833 Aug. 24; Mss.B.H334
  - Hart, Charles Henry to I. Minis Hays, 1908 Sep. 23; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Hartshorne, J. to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
    Friday morning.
  - Haughton, Samuel to Isaac Hays, 1861 Mar. 27
  - Hayes, Isaac Israel to William Parker Foulke, 1860 Apr. 25; Mss.B.H334
    1988 256ms
    Separated Materials note
    Moved to the William Parker Foulke Papers, Mss.B.F826.
  - Hays, Isaac - Essay Deploring the State of Letters in America, undated; Mss.B.H334
  - Hays, Isaac - Scientific Notes on Pneumatics, undated; Mss.B.H334
  - Hays, Isaac to unknown recipients, 1839-1841; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1839 Oct. 24, 1841 Dec. 6
  - Hays, Isaac from unidentified correspondents, 1844-undated; Mss.B.H334
    4 items: 1844 Jan. 24, 1848 Mar. 16, 1849 Mar. 15, undated fragment
  - Hays, I. Minis - List of Sales and Exchange by States and Countries, undated; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Hays, I. Minis - Notes, undated; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Hays, Samuel - Will, 1824 May 21; Mss.B.H334
  - Hays, Samuel from Isaac Hays, 1819 Aug. 14
  - Hays, Sarah to Sarah Minis Hays, 1834 Mar. 16; Mss.B.H334
    Addressed to Sarah Ann Minis prior to her marriage.
  - Hays, Sarah Minis, 1851-undated; Mss.B.H334,334.1
    3 items: 1851 Dec. 3 from Ellen; undated Aug. 5 letter from her mother, Dinah (Cohen) Minis; undated birthday wishes to daughter Henrietta (with a postscript from Aunt Rea).
    Sarah Minis Hays was Sarah Ann Minis prior to her marriage, often called Sally.
  - Hays, Sarah Minis to I. Minis Hays, 1871
    2 items: 1871 Aug. 14, 1871 Aug. 20
  - Hays, Sarah Minis from Isaac Hays, 1829-1833; Mss.B.H334
    4 items: 1929 Oct. 25, Jul. 19; 1832 Feb. 11; 1833 Nov. 19. Addressed to Sarah Ann Minis, prior to their marriage.
    1967 525ms (1833), 1967 940ms (1829, 1832)
  - Hayward, George to Isaac Hays, 1829-1832; Mss.B.H334
    5 items: 1829 Aug. 8, Sep. 3, Nov. 5; 1832 Feb. 24, Mar. 5
    1967 940ms, 1967 525ms (1829 Aug. 8)
  - Haywood, James to Isaac Hays, 1848 Dec. 3; Mss.B.H334
  - Henry, Joseph to Isaac Hays, 1865 Aug. 12; Mss.B.H334
  - Henry, Uncle to Rose, 1864 Jan. 29; Mss.B.H334.1
    Regarding the obituary of Dr. Willie.
  - Hewson, Thomas Tickell to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
    Wednesday, October 30
  - Hirst, Barton Cooke to I. Minis Hays, 1917 Apr. 10; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Hoben, Mr. to I. Minis Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334.1
    On same sheet as Judge Pennypacker to I. Minis Hays, undated.
  - Hodge, H. Lenox to Isaac Hays, 1871 May 18; Mss.B.H334
  - Hodges, R. M. to I. Minis Hays, 1872 Nov. 17; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1846-1848; Mss.B.H334
    3 items: 1846 Apr. 9; 1848 May 12, Jun. 2
  - Holmes, T. to Isaac Hays, 1852-1853; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1852 Jul. 20, 1853 Feb. 21
  - Hood, Mrs. to I. Minis Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
    March 17.
  - Hooker, W. to Isaac Hays, 1851 Oct. 1; Mss.B.H334
  - Hooker, Sir William Jackson to Isaac Hays, 1824 Mar. 2; Mss.B.H334
  - Hookers, Edward to Isaac Hays, 1844 Aug. 17; Mss.B.H334
  - Horatio to "dear cousins", undated; Mss.B.H334.1
    January 25. To "my fair cousins Miss Ellen, Miss Lillie and Miss Annie."
  - Horner, W. E. to Isaac Hays, 1852 May 23; Mss.B.H334
  - Horsley, Victor to I. Minis Hays, 1888 Sep. 23; Mss.B.H334.1
    See: 509:L56.45 Letters of Scientists
  - Howe, S. G. to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
    Howe to Hays, June 3. On the same sheet is Edward James to Hays, undated.
  - Ingersoll, Mrs. Charles E. and Phebe W. - Invitation, undated; Mss.B.H334
    Invitation for Saturday, Sept. 14.
  - International Medical Congress. - Invitation, 1876 Sep. 8; Mss.B.H334
  - Jackson, Charles J. to Isaac Hays, 1848 Apr. 17; Mss.B.H334
  - Jackson, James to Isaac Hays, 1834-1851; Mss.B.H334
    1967 940ms (1830s), 1967 525ms (1851)
    4 items: 1834 Dec. 23, [1838] Nov. 24, 1839 Feb. 14, 1851 Aug. 16
  - Jackson, John to Isaac Hays, 1843-1855; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1843 Jun. 13, 1855 Sep. 10
  - Jackson, S. to Isaac Hays, 1832 Jun. 28; Mss.B.H334
  - Jacob, Dr. to Isaac Hays, 1850 Jan. 12; Mss.B.H334
  - Jacobi, Abraham to Isaac M. Hays, 1885-undated; Mss.B.H334
    7 items: 1885 May 13, Jun. 6, Jul. 3, Jul. 7, Jul. 12; (2) undated
  - James, Edward to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
    On the same sheet as S. G. Howe to Hays, June 3 undated.
  - James, Thomas C. to Isaac Hays, 1824 Aug. 4; Mss.B.H334
  - Jayne, C. W. to Isaac Hays, 1846 Feb. 1; Mss.B.H334
  - Johnson, Reverdy to Isaac Hays, 1862 Apr. 1; Mss.B.H334
  - Joseph, Henry to I. Minis Hays, 1893 Nov.; Mss.B.H334.1
    1967 525ms (Nov. 20), 1967 562ms (Nov. 29)
    2 items: 1893 Nov. 20, 29
  - Joseph, J. H. to I. Minis Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334.1
    March.
  - Jusserand, J. J. to I. Minis Hays, 1923; Mss.B.H334.1
    3 items: Mar. 25, Apr. 2, Apr. 19
  - Kane, Elisha Kent to Isaac Hays, 1852; Mss.B.H334
    Monday A.M. Authority for date of Summer 1852, G. W. Carner.
  - Kane, John Kintzing to Isaac Hays, 1839 Jan. 1; Mss.B.H334
  - Keating, William Hypolitus to Isaac Hays, 1822-1825; Mss.B.H334
    7 items: 1822 Dec. 31 (3); 1824 Dec. 28 (3); 1825 Aug. 1
    1967 334ms, 1967 940ms (1825)
  - Keen, William Williams to I. Minis Hays, 1907 Oct. 20; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Kelleys, Robert H. to I. Minis Hays, 1900 May 8; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Kennedy, Emory to Isaac Hays, 1839 Dec. 6; Mss.B.H334
  - Kimbeck, R. A. to I. Minis Hays, 1885 Jul. 6; Mss.B.H334.1
  - King, Richard to Isaac Hays, 1849 Feb. 6; Mss.B.H334
  - Kirckhoff, Chevalier de to Isaac Hays, 1833 Apr. 19; Mss.B.H334
  - Knight, Jonathan to Isaac Hays, 1854-1857; Mss.B.H334
    3 items: 1854 Aug. 4; 1857 Apr. 1, 14
  - Krock, Albert to Isaac Hays, 1840 Oct. 11; Mss.B.H334
  - Lampato, F. to Giuseppe Togno, 1834 May 15; Mss.B.H334
  - Lawrence, William to Isaac Hays, 1844-1847; Mss.B.H334
    1967 525ms (1844), 1967 562ms (1847), 1967 940ms (1846)
    3 items: 1944 Feb. 23, 1846 Feb. 4, 1847 Sep. 4
  - Le Plaz to Isaac Hays, 1834 Mar. 1; Mss.B.H334
    Le Plaz was Secretary of Ecole Royal des Mines. On receipt of 1933's Descriptions of the inferior maxillary bones of mastodons, in the cabinet of the American Philosophical Society, with remarks on the genus Tetracaulodon.
  - Lea, Arthur H. to I. Minis Hays, 1909 Oct. 24; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Lee, Henry to Isaac Hays, 1839 Mar. 15; Mss.B.H334
  - Lea, Henry Charles to I. Minis Hays, 1876-1909; Mss.B.H334.1
    3 items: 1876 International Medical Congress invitation; 1906 Dec. 17 and 1909 Oct. 22 to I. Minis Hays
  - Lea, Isaac to Isaac Hays, 1874-1879; Mss.B.H334
    1967 525ms (1874), 1967 562ms (1879)
    2 items: 1874 Sep. 10, 1879 Jan. 1
  - Lea, William H.
    Unlocated June 2011.
  - Leland, Charles G. to Isaac Hays, 1869 Apr. 20; Mss.B.H334
  - Lesueur, Charles Alexandre to Isaac Hays, 1827-1832; Mss.B.H334.b; 1.0 vol. Bound volume. (Volume 1, Reel 1363)
    Bound volume also includes correspondence from Charles Lucien Bonaparte, George Ord, and Thomas Say.
  - Lewell, Thomas to Isaac Hays, 1830-1835; Mss.B.H334
    3 items: 1830 May 18, 1834 Dec. 30, 1835 Oct. 15
  - Livingston, E. to B. F. Peale, 1834 Jul. 3; Mss.B.H334
  - Longmore, Robert to Isaac Hays, 1873 May 7; Mss.B.H334
  - McMarter, John Bach to H. LaBarr Jaynes, 1906 Dec. 27; Mss.B.H334.1
  - McWilliam, J. O. to Isaac Hays, 1849 Jun. 1; Mss.B.H334
  - McWilliams, Dr. to Isaac Hays, 1847 Jul. 1; Mss.B.H334
  - Mackerosie(?), John N. to I. Minis Hays, 1885 Jul. 1; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Mary from I. Minis Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334.1
    On same sheet as Thomson to Hays, 1912 Dec. 5.
  - Madden, Thomas More to Isaac Hays, 1871 May 24; Mss.B.H334
  - Marsh, George P. to Isaac Hays, 1845-1848; Mss.B.H334
    1967 525ms (1845), 1967 562ms (1848)
    2 items: 1845 Dec. 2, 1848 Jan. 3
  - Maskell
    Unlocated June 2011. Possibly Robert Maskell Patterson.
  - Mastin, C. H. to I. Minis Hays, 1885 Aug. 11; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Meddlemore, Richard, 1837-1839; Mss.B.H334
    1967 562ms (1837, 1838), 1967 940ms (1839)
    3 items: 1837 Sep. 17, 1838 Oct., 1839 Dec. 20
  - Medical and Physical Society of Bombay to Isaac Hays, 1853 Feb. 1; Mss.B.H334
  - Medical Society of Hamburg to Isaac Hays, 1841 Jan.; Mss.B.H334
  - Meigs, Charles Delucena to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
  - Meigs, H. I. to I. Minis Hays, 1908 Oct. 30; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Miller, Leslie W. to Mr. Jayne, 1906 Dec. 12; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Minis, Ellen to Sarah Minis Hays, 1855-undated; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1855 Aug. 14, undated Jul. 27
  - Minis, Isaac to Isaac Hays, 1833 Dec. 7; Mss.B.H334
  - Mitchell, J. K. to Isaac Hays, 1839-undated; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1839 Oct. 21; undated
  - Montgomery, Archibald R. to I. Minis Hays, 1908 Nov. 3; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Montreal Mechanics' Institute to Isaac Hays, 1829 Oct. 8; 1967
  - Moore, Charles H. to Isaac Hays, 1858 May 12; Mss.B.H334
  - Morton, W. G. to Isaac Hays, 1850 Sep. 23; Mss.B.H334
  - Moses, Horace to Isaac Minis, undated; Mss.B.H334
  - Mott, Valentine to Isaac Hays, 1841 Dec. 2; Mss.B.H334
  - National Institute for the Promotion of Science - Printed extract of minutes, 1832 Jun. 13; Mss.B.H334
  - National Medical Association - Resolutions, 1847-undated; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: May 1847 (including drafts), undated
  - Norsk Magazin for Lagevidenskaben to Isaac Hays, 1842 Jun. 28; Mss.B.H334
  - Noyer, Henry D. to I. Minis Hays, 1885 Jul. 31; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Nuttall, Thomas to Isaac Hays, 1786-1859; Mss.B.H334
    Other Finding Aids note
  - Oppenheim, I. to Isaac Hays, 1839 Mar. 25; Mss.B.H334
  - Ord, George to Isaac Hays, 1828-1855; Mss.B.H334.b; 1.0 vol. Bound volume. (Volume 1, Reel 1363)
    Bound volume also includes correspondence from Charles Lucien Bonaparte, Thomas Say, and C. A. Lesueur.
  - Osler, Grace R. to Isaac Minis Hays, 1924-1925; Mss.B.H334.1
    1967 525ms (1924 Nov. 7), 1967 562ms
    4 items: 1924 Sep. 16, 1924 Nov. 7, 1925 Jan. 22, reply from Hays
  - Otto, C. to Isaac Hays, 1832-1843; Mss.B.H334
    6 items: 1832 Oct. 20, 1835 Aug., 1840 Apr. 13, 1841 Apr. 13, 1842 Aug., 1843 Apr. 13
  - Parker, Francis L. to I. Minis Hays, 1885; Mss.B.H334.1
    2 items: 1885 Jul. 24, Aug. 11
  - Pascalis, Felix to Isaac Hays, 1828 Aug. 15; Mss.B.H334
  - Patterson, Robert Maskell, 1831 Nov. 13; Mss.B.H334
  - Paul, John R. to Isaac Hays, 1837 Jan. 29; Mss.B.H334
  - Peace, Edwin to Isaac Hays, 1832 Apr.; Mss.B.H334
  - Peale, Reubens to Isaac Hays, 1831 Jul. 21; Mss.B.H334
  - Peaslee, E. R. to Isaac Hays, 1849 Feb. 20; Mss.B.H334
  - Peirson, A. L. to Isaac Hays, 1847 Nov. 17; Mss.B.H334
  - Pemberton, Henry to H. LaBarr Jayne, 1906 Dec. 12; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Pennock, C. W. to Isaac Hays, 1850 Mar. 31; Mss.B.H334
  - Pennypacker, Judge to I. Minis Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334.1
    On same sheet as Hoben to Hays, undated.
  - Pepper, John to I. Minis Hays, 1885 Jul. 4; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Phillips, Barnet to Isaac Hays, 1846 Apr. 6; Mss.B.H334
  - Phillips, William to I. Minis Hays, 1904 Jan. 1; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Pouralban, Baron de to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
    September 26.
  - Priestly, (?) to Isaac Hays, 1889 Mar. 2; Mss. B. H334
  - Purves, G. C. to I. Minis Hays, 1909 Nov. 16; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Putman, Herbert to I. Minis Hays, 1900 May 1; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Ramsey, Frank M. - Quinine pill recipe, 1882 Dec. 23; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Randall, J. to Isaac Hays, 1847 Jul. 24; Mss.B.H334
  - Randolph, J. to Isaac Hays, 1839 Oct. 21; Mss.B.H334
    On same sheet as letter from Emerson.
  - Ranking, William Harcourt to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
  - Reed, William B. to Isaac Hays, 1827-1850; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1827 Jan. 27, 1850 Aug. 16
  - Reyburn, John E. to I. Minis Hays, 1908 Feb. 15; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Rhode Island Medical Society to Isaac Hays, 1858 Jul. 28; Mss.B.H334
  - Rigby, Edward, 1843 Mar. 9; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: Letter to Isaac Hays, letter to Lea & Blanchard
  - Riofrey, Bernard to Isaac Hays, 1849 Nov. 26; Mss.B.H334
  - Ross, A. to Isaac Hays, 1853 Nov. 23; Mss.B.H334
  - Ryan, M. to Isaac Hays, 1840 Feb. 4; Mss.B.H334
  - Say, Thomas to Isaac Hays, 1826-1832; Mss.B.H334.b; 1.0 vol. Bound volume. (Volume 1, Reel 1363)
    Bound volume also includes correspondence from Charles Lucien Bonaparte, George Ord, and C. A. Lesueur.
  - Sergeant, J. D. to Samuel Bradford, 1876 Mar. 6; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Sewall, Thomas to Isaac Hays, 1827-1829; Mss.B.H334
    8 items: 1827 Aug. 4, 31, Sep. 14, Oct. 11, Nov. 8, Dec. 5; 1828 Mar. 3; 1829 Apr. 30
    1967 525ms (1829 Apr. 30, 1828 Mar. 3), 1967 940ms (1827 Aug. 4, 31, Sep. 14, Oct. 11, Nov. 8, Dec. 5)
  - Sewell, Thomas to Isaac Hays, 1830-1843; Mss.B.H334
    1967 525ms (1830 Oct. 20, 1831 Mar. 12, 1837 Apr. 24, 1839 Apr. 30, 1843 Dec. 14), 1967 562ms (1830 Jan. 3, 1831 Jan. 31, 1833 Feb. 11, 1836 Aug. 28), 1967 940ms (1831 Nov. 2; 1833 Nov. 7; 1836 Mar. 21; 1843 Mar. 6)
    13 items: 1830 Jan. 3, 1830 Oct. 20, 1831 Jan. 31, 1831 Mar. 12, 1831 Nov. 2, 1833 Feb. 11, 1833 Nov. 7, 1836 Mar. 21, 1836 Aug. 28, 1837 Apr. 24, 1839 Apr. 30, 1843 Mar. 6, 1843 Dec. 14
  - Shoemaker, John V. to I. Minis Hays, 1885; Mss.B.H334
    1885 June 8, 9, 16 Shoemaker to Hays regarding AMA Committe business and scheduling; undated postscript (Hays to Billings?) regarding $400 appropriation.
    1885 May 10 Billings to Hays (possibly a copy) moved to Billings folder.
  - Sieveking, E. H. to Isaac Hays, 1858 Nov. 4; Mss.B.H334
  - Smith, A. H. to I. Minis Hays, 1885 Jul. 24; Mss.B.H334
  - Smith, Joseph M. to Isaac Hays, 1834-1838; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1834 Dec. 3, 1838 Mar. 12
    1967 940ms (1834), 1967 525ms (1838)
  - Smith, Lloyd P. to I. Minis Hays, 1883 Jan. 6; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Smith, Nathan Ryno to Isaac Hays, 1837-1838; Mss.B.H334
    6 items: 1837 Apr. 23; 1838 Jun. 13, Jul. 6, Sep. 6, Sep. 12, Sep. 14
  - Smyth, Dr. to Isaac Hays, 1844 Jul. 5; Mss.B.H334
  - Société Anonyme du Bulletin Universe to Isaac Hays, 1830 Mar. 10; Mss.B.H334
  - Société Universelle d'Opthalmologie to Isaac Hays, 1862 Feb. 8; Mss.B.H334
  - Sowerby, James de Carle to Isaac Hays, 1822-1825; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1822 Dec. 16, 1825 Aug. 22
  - Sparks, Jared to Isaac Hays, 1826 Jul. 29; Mss.B.H334
  - Stankey, Thomas to Isaac Hays, 1878 May 9; Mss.B.H334
  - Sternberg, George M. to I. Minis Hays, 1881 Feb. 8; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Stevens, A. H. to Isaac Hays, 1848; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1848 May 15, Aug. 11
    1967 525ms (Aug), 940ms (May)
  - Stillé, Alfred from I. Minis Hays, 1898-undated; Mss.B.H334.1
    2 items: 1898 Aug. 5, undated.
  - Streatfield, J. J. to Isaac Hays, 1858 May 4; Mss.B.H334
  - Swainson, William to Isaac Hays, 1827 Mar. 17; Mss.B.H334
  - Swett, John A. to Isaac Hays, 1844; Mss.B.H334
    2 items: 1844 Oct. 31, Nov. 12
  - Tartini, Ferdinando to Isaac Hays, 1840 Dec. 28; Mss.B.H334
  - Thiebaut de Barneaud, Arsenne to Isaac Hays, 1826 Aug. 17; Mss.B.H334
  - Thomson, John to I. Minis Hays, 1912 Dec. 5; Mss.B.H334.1
    Invitation acceptance is on the same sheet as a letter from Hays to Mary.
  - Thomson, William to I. Minis Hays, 1903 May 27; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Ticknor, George to Isaac Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
  - Toner, Joseph M.
    Extract of a letter. Includes photocopies of the original.
  - Tucker, George to Isaac Hays, 1858 May 7; Mss.B.H334
  - Tulman, R. P. to Mrs. G. B. Hays, 1930 May 1; Mss.B.H334.1
  - Twining, W. to Isaac Hays, 1831-1833; Mss.B.H334
    1967 562ms (1833 Mar. 22), 525ms
    4 items: 1831 Jan. 10; 1833 Mar. 22 (2), Nov. 26
  - Tyson, James to I. Minis Hays, 1910 May 9; Mss.B.H334.1
  - University of Pennsylvania Graduating Class to I. Minis Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
  - Van Buren, William to Isaac Hays, 1845 Aug. 18; Mss.B.H334
  - Vigors, N. A. to G. B. Sowerby, 1826 Dec. 8; Mss.B.H334
    On same sheet as C. L. Bonaparte to Vigors, 1826 Dec. 19.
  - W?, G. W. to I. Minis Hays, undated; Mss.B.H334
    July 9, regarding finances and repairs.
  - Wade, Dr. to Isaac Hays, 1862 Jun. 5; Mss.B.H334